[door opens, closes]
[Chinatsu] Good morning.
Good morning to you.
You're up early as usual.
Yep, a new term's starting.
Whoa, you've got bedhead.
Like, right here.
What?
[Taiki grunts]
We must look stupid!
[Taiki] It seems like
ever since we went to the beach,
that awkward feeling between
Chinatsu and me has disappeared.
EIMEI PRIVATE HIGH SCHOOL
Nothing's really changed.
I still like Chinatsu.
She's still putting everything
into basketball,
and living at my house
so she can keep playing.
But even more than before,
it's like we're...
[opening theme song playing]
BLUE BOX
CULTURAL FESTIVAL
[Niina] It's been decided that our class
will put on the play Snow White,
with our own Hina Chono as the lead!
EPISODE 16
UNFAIR WOMAN
- It's gonna be a smash.
- [clapping]
Never fear! You're all safe aboard my ark!
- Your ark?
- [Hina] Don't ya get it?
Can she even memorize lines?
She's certainly used to
performing for an audience.
Huh? Taiki!
You're the class representative,
so you need to be a leader,
and keep us in line!
Sure, I'm the class rep,
but I just take care of the small stuff.
Shimazaki's in charge. She's the director.
[Hina] What are you talking about?
Don't put it all on Niina.
You have to make sure everything stays
on track, even when we run into problems.
Then don't cause problems
in the first place.
I mean, obviously I'm excited.
To the extent that I'm able,
I'll be happy to help out.
[Yoshiki] Inomata!
Here's the program for our play.
Can you turn it in
to the second-year chair?
Sure thing.
Be back later.
There goes our worker bee.
Maybe this role is part
of his fitness training.
[Kyo] Hm.
So, hey.
It's not like Taiki said anything to me...
You told him, though... that you like him?
- What!
- [girl] You are so loud.
[Hina] Uh, just a vocal exercise.
You okay?
[Hina sighs]
Taiki has feelings for Chinatsu,
and they live together.
Oh. Well, aren't you the nosy one.
- Wait are you worried about me?
- I'm not.
'Cause that's just how it is!
- [Kyo] Hm?
- I realized I like Taiki,
and that's all there is to it!
[Niina] Hina!
[Hina] Coming!
[Kyo] Still, it can't be easy for her.
[knocking at door]
Excuse me. Anyone here?
- [Chinatsu] Taiki.
- [grunts softly]
Something happen?
I stopped by to turn in
our program to Sasaki.
Oh, gotcha. Well, everyone's out preparing
for the Cultural Festival right now.
I could turn it in?
Yes, that'd be great.
- Are you gonna come in?
- Ah. Oh, right, excuse me.
[Taiki] Entering a second-year classroom
freaks me out.
You have a great spot in here, Chinatsu.
By the window, and in the back.
We just redid the seating chart.
It's a new semester, so did we.
So then where is your spot?
[grunts] Uh...
Actually, here.
That's too bad.
Why, what makes you say that?
'Cause if we were in the same year,
we'd sit next to each other.
It's only because you didn't wait
one more year to be born.
Then you could've let me
copy your homework.
Do your own homework!
You know, you sit in the back,
but don't seem like
you'd sleep during class.
Yep. No sleeping here.
But you seem like one
who'd sleep during class, Taiki.
And when you'd be up next
to answer a question,
you'd stay asleep
even when I'd try to wake you.
All right, next up. Inomata.
Inomata!
[yells] Yes!
Third section under question one.
Um, it...
Uh... three times pi divided by four.
Correct. Make sure
you pay attention in class.
Yes.
[chuckles]
[wind blowing]
I think you're gonna have to figure out
how to skip a grade, then.
There's no way!
I'm joking.
Kano!
I think I'm gonna head back.
Okay. I'll pass this on.
[Taiki] If I could skip a grade, I would.
From the beginning,
we've been in different grades,
played different sports.
And all I could do
was stare at her through the net.
This just reminds me that we
wouldn't have gotten to know each other
if we hadn't lived together.
- [Taiki] I'm home.
- [Yukiko] That must've been hard.
[Taiki] Someone's here.
- [Yukiko] I'm sorry to trouble you.
- Hey, everyone.
- Huh?
- Hi there, Taiki! Long time no see!
Chinatsu's mom? What are you doing here?
You're back in Japan?
Chinatsu's grandpa collapsed
the other day,
I hopped on a plane as soon as I could.
What? Is he going to be all right?
He'll live, if that's what you're asking,
but he has surgery
scheduled for next month.
So I'm thinking of renting
a furnished apartment
- month-to-month for a while.
- Oh, I see.
That's why Chinatsu will be going
to live with her mom for the time being.
What?
[Chinatsu's mom] Thank you, Taiki.
It was very nice of you
to help carry all our luggage.
No worries.
[Yukiko] It's a good thing you found
such a nice apartment month-to-month.
Yes, we're lucky.
Although, it's not as close
to their school as your house is,
but we'll figure it out.
I know it's only for a month
till her grandfather has surgery,
but we're really going to miss her.
Won't we, Taiki?
Huh? Uh... Oh, yes, we will.
Don't be shy now. [chuckles]
[Taiki] I'll be waiting
for you in the car.
Taiki... here's your key back.
[Taiki] Uh, thank you.
No way, I should be thanking you.
I know practice is soon.
And you have a practice game
at another school, right?
Yeah, at Nishijo.
Gotcha.
So, tomorrow. See you at morning gym.
[gasps softly]
[Taiki] Oh, yeah.
We may not be living together right now
but we have gotten closer!
We can talk at morning practice!
Same as always!
Good morning!
Huh? Maybe I'm too early.
She lives farther away now.
- So I guess things won't be the same.
- [footsteps]
Good morning.
Aw, man, if it isn't Haryu.
What a surprise.
You're never here this early.
My mom was heading out
for something and woke me up.
[Taiki] I've got a bad feeling about this.
It's pretty nice out today.
Why don't we go for a run?
[Taiki] This guy's
full of energy this early?
- And, we're going.
- Huh? Wha... Wait...
I don't mind running,
but why's it gotta be today of all days?
CONGRATS ON NATIONALS
[groans]
I didn't get to see Chinatsu after all.
I can't believe he made me
run the entire practice!
It was kinda weird, though,
that Chinatsu wasn't the first one there.
[Niina] Inomata.
Claps reps have a festival meeting.
[Taiki] I know
her living situation's changed,
but she made it to morning practice,
no problem,
when she moved into my house.
Wait, what if she didn't come to school?
SEMINAR ROOM
Maybe she got sick.
[inaudible]
[exclaims softly]
Thank goodness.
If I didn't see her in the gym,
or run into her somewhere else,
I wouldn't have known she was at school.
[gasps]
- Kano.
- [Chinatsu] Yes!
[grunts, sighs]
[sighs]
What's up with you?
- [Taiki] Stomach ache.
- Oh, so you're fine, then.
HOW TO SKIP A GRADE
[Kyo] You're joking.
Yep. Joking.
I guess there's no point in worrying
about things in my life
that I have no control over.
- [Haryu] Taiki, you're up!
- All right!
Ready!
- [girl 1] Keep it up!
- [girl 2] Ten more seconds!
- [Chinatsu] You got this!
- [Taiki gasps]
- Keep going. Don't stop.
- [Taiki] That was Chinatsu's voice.
This reminds me
of before we started living together.
Small things like this made me happy.
[rackets whooshing]
[Coach Yuasa] All right, guys!
Time to wrap it up!
Just a little longer.
[Coach Yuasa] Ten, nine, eight...
[Taiki] Roger that. We'll clean up.
- Where's girls' basketball?
- [Kyo] They left already.
[grunts] How'd I miss it?
[Taiki] I was hoping to see her
one more time before I went home.
Today really wore me out.
The morning run,
helping with the school festival,
then practice on top of that.
I wonder if Haryu's gonna
wake up early again tomorrow.
I need to fill out the
Equipment Sign-Out Form when I get home.
But even when I get home,
Chinatsu's not gonna be there.
One whole month, huh?
I'll try to talk to her more
starting tomorrow.
Yeah! We're not under the same roof,
so I'll find ways
to talk to her at school!
And, anyway...
[wind blowing]
...this is going to become
the norm at some point.
I'm home.
- Oh, welcome back.
- Huh?
Why are you here?
Wait, is she staying with us after all?
Aren't you staying at the apartment?
Yeah, but I left a few things behind.
Oh, okay.
And then, there was something
that I wanted to say to you.
You weren't there this morning.
Yes, I was!
But, Haryu made me go on a run with him.
[Chinatsu] Haryu did?
[Taiki] Actually, the one
who wasn't there was you!
[Chinatsu] Well, I got
on the wrong train by accident.
- So you...
- But...
I ran to school from the station.
[gasps softly]
[panting]
[Taiki] I was right.
We have gotten closer.
Well, we'll try again tomorrow.
See you then.
[student as witch] Beautiful young lady,
I have a gift for you.
Oh, my! What a beautiful apple!
Its skin is so red and glossy,
its bottom is so plump,
and its form so pleasing.
It looks to be the sweetest apple
I've seen in quite some time.
[student as witch] I dare say
you're right, young miss!
Its mellow aroma and its...
Aroma...
I'm so sorry.
No, don't worry, you're doing great.
You've done a lot in a short time.
Hina's a lot better at acting
than I thought.
I'm not sure about the script
we're using, though.
Keeping your confidence while being
in front of people is a skill, too.
[Taiki] That's true.
The costumes you're making,
they look promising.
Being put in a situation
where you're forced to do something,
you'll find you often get better at it.
BRO! BRO!
Like making things for your siblings.
[Taiki] It's great seeing everyone
giving it their all.
Does anyone here have the key
for storage room B?
I know that Taniguchi had it earlier.
[girl] Hey, do we have any more
packing tape? We're running out.
I'll get it.
- [boy] How many desks did we need again?
- It's eight!
Oh, shoot! The safety check-up meeting
is about to start!
- [Taiki] I can go.
- Sorry about that!
And thank you!
[girl] Inomata's more reliable
than you'd expect!
He always gets to things right away,
and he's easy to talk to, it's so helpful.
[chuckles softly]
Make sure to review evacuation routes.
SCHOOL STORE
[Taiki] Packing tape, and I guess
I'll get some permanent markers, too.
[both gasp]
Well, good morning.
Good morning...
Wait, we already did this
at practice earlier.
I felt like "good morning"
was appropriate since it's you.
Hm?
What was your class doing?
It's a cafe, right?
Yeah. We're going all out
with the outfits for the waitresses!
There are waitresses?
Welcome to our cafe!
[Taiki] That'd be awesome,
but I don't wanna see her serving
other people in that outfit.
The thing is,
since I'm the class representative,
I won't be serving the customers.
Huh?
[Taiki] Never mind, I wish
I could see her in that outfit!
And then your class
is doing Snow White, right?
With Hina as the lead?
That's right.
But since I'm overseeing everything,
I won't be acting in it.
Huh? I thought you'd be playing
Prince Charming.
I couldn't!
I wouldn't be any good at that!
Prince Charming
is being played by a tall girl!
Okay, I see.
Oh, there you are, Taiki.
Our teacher was looking for...
Oh.
Hello, Chinatsu.
Hi, Hina.
- Okay, well, good luck, then.
- Yeah, you, too, good luck.
[Taiki] So, what's up?
[Hina] We don't have enough supplies
or something.
These and... this.
We need all these?
[Chinatsu's mom]
Chinatsu, the bath is all yours.
Okay, thanks.
Koyuki, you knew, didn't you?
You knew that I have a crush on Kumai.
And yet, you went
on a business trip together!
It was work,
there was nothing I could do about it.
You think that I don't understand that?
But that isn't the point!
I'm talking about
how you're being with me, Koyuki!
- Koyuki really is an unfair woman.
- Hm?
You can't argue with someone
who uses work as an excuse.
If I had to guess, I'd bet she's probably
been leading him on the whole time.
[Chinatsu] Mm.
If she really wasn't interested,
there are all kinds of ways she could have
created some distance between them.
Everyone has their own way of pursuing
romantic relationships, obviously,
but being indecisive
and leading people on is pretty unfair.
Right, hon? Don't you think so?
Mm-hm.
[Chinatsu] Mom bought this rubber ducky
as a souvenir.
I am being kinda unfair, aren't I?
I am.
Even when I know Hina likes Taiki.
I want to go somewhere.
[sighs]
If I were Hina, I wouldn't want me
saying that kind of thing to him.
But...
at that time...
the two of them weren't dating yet.
[groans]
But...
when I feel like I need someone
to be there for me...
- [boy 1] Inomata!
- [boy 2] Inomata!
Right here!
So this is what it means
to be up to your ears in work.
[Taiki panting]
Geez, I'm sorry I'm so late.
You look worn out.
We're playing doubles right now, though.
[gulping loudly]
[Taiki] I'll just drink some water.
Ah!
I knew what I was signing up for, but wow.
I don't want to practice
any less than I usually do,
but I have all the prep for the festival.
Taiki, I know that it's difficult.
Nishida?
Indeed, time flies, and you can't
get it back once you've spent it.
However, you've had a role
bestowed upon you,
so you must continue to fight your battle
within what is possible,
until the very end.
And my role in this is
to help an underclassman
get as much practice in as they like.
Okay... Nishida.
Captain!
- [laughing]
- Nishida's laying it on pretty thick
since the seniors retired
and he became captain.
We all liked him
'cause he was so laid back.
- Good luck, Vice-Captain.
- [Haryu] Not my problem.
[Nishida] Whom amongst you
used the term "laid back" just now?
[boy] This act is weirding me out.
- [Taiki] Use your elbow more.
- [boy] Like this?
I get it now. Thanks, Mr. Inomata.
- Appreciate it.
- Yeah, you're welcome.
Oh, Mr. Inomata.
What is it?
Junior high?
Yeah, first-year badminton.
Needed some help.
It's nice having
both schools combined, right?
Mr. Inomata.
You seem to like calling me that.
Uh, I just thought you really looked
the part of the upperclassman.
Well, first-years are still pretty short,
that's for sure.
But when you were
in your first year of middle school,
you were probably his height, too.
You wouldn't know how tall I was then.
[Chinatsu grunts]
[Taiki] Wait. She got serious.
And anyway, I'm gonna get a lot taller.
In the future,
I plan to grow to be about this tall.
No fair.
I think I've just about
stopped growing already.
Privilege of being a guy.
I'm gonna widen the gap before long!
[Chinatsu sighs]
[Taiki exclaims]
I think the height you are is perfect.
Oh... 'kay.
Or I'd say maybe this tall.
Wouldn't that mean
that I've stopped growing, then, though?
[laughs]
[Taiki] Don't laugh at that.
At this height,
I'm certainly closer to her face, but...
As a man, I'd like to be a bit taller.
"The seven dwarfs said to me."
"'Make sure to be careful...'"
"Careful..."
"And no matter who may come here,
you must not open the door."
Isn't that it?
You have good memory.
I hear the rehearsals while I'm sewing.
You should've been
one of our actors, too, Kyo.
No way, I'm not good
with romantic stories at all.
You do kinda give off that vibe.
Snow White has to deal
with misfortune and struggle,
so I empathize with her.
But marrying a prince
who shows up out of nowhere,
I don't understand at all.
[Hina] Hm.
- That's very feminist.
- Hm?
I guess we've never talked
about this before, but...
is there anyone you like?
What are you asking for?
You always give advice as an outsider,
I just wondered how it was for you.
[Kyo sighs]
[Hina] Mm.
Right now, nobody.
"Right now"?
She going out with someone,
so I gave up on her.
Mm. Sorry.
It's okay.
That's why when I see you
going after somebody like Taiki
who has feelings for another person,
I pity you.
Pity?
I'm also impressed.
Having said that, Taiki's my friend.
I'm not gonna root for you to end up
with him or anything like that.
Oh, come on, gimme a leg up!
- No way. That spells trouble.
- Oh, c'mon.
[Hina] So, who is this girl you liked?
[Kyo] I'll never tell you.
[Hina] Is it someone I know?
- [Kyo] Who can say.
- [Hina groans]
[Hina] I'm Snow White,
yet somehow running errands.
Go make some copies.
GUIDANCE COUNSELOR
[Hina] Excuse me.
Oh.
Good afternoon.
You need the copier?
Oh. Take as much time as you need.
Your class is putting on a café, right?
[Chinatsu] Mm.
Taiki told me about it.
By the way...
I told him.
I told Taiki that I like him.
[gasps softly]
[closing theme song playing]